A Guide to the Cayce / Reilly School of Massage Collection, 1985-2015
The Edgar Cayce Foundation
The Edgar Cayce Foundation
Cayce / Reilly School of Massage Collection, 1985-2015
The Edgar Cayce Foundation, Virginia Beach, Virginia
Coll. 29
0.4 Linear Feet 1 box.
Arrangement
Collection arranged alphabetically by material type.
Biographical / Historical
The Cayce / Reilly School of Massage opened in 1987 as the Harold J. Reilly School of Massotherapy. The school's curriculum combines the concepts of holism, healing, and personal transformation contained in the Edgar Cayce material and the massage style drawn from these concepts by Dr. Harold J. Reilly. Dr. Reilly was a physiotherapist and a pioneer in the field of massage therapy. He began receiving cases at his New York City clinic from Edgar Cayce in 1930, almost two years before they met in person. Reilly created the trademarked Cayce/Reilly Massage, a particular style of Swedish Massage he developed from information suggested in the Cayce readings.
Scope and Contents
This collection includes publications, staff and student records generated by the Cayce / Reilly School of Massage in Virginia Beach, Virginia.
- Box 1
  - alumni newsletter [The Healing Touch], 1995-2005; Folder 1:1
  - audiocassette [Harold J. Reilly School of Massotherapy first graduation], 1987; Folder 1:2
  - catalog [Anatomical Chart Company], 1986; Folder 1:3
  - certificate to operate, 1987; Folder 1:4
  - certification letters, 1986; Folder 1:5
  - class evaluations, 1985; Folder 1:6
  - correspondence [staff], 1985-1993; Folder 1:7
  - Five-Year Plan [A.R.E. Health Services and the Harold J. Reilly School of Massotherapy], 1994; Folder 1:8
  - minutes [Health and Wellness Committee], 1993-1995; Folder 1:9
  - minutes [Hearing on the Regulation of Allied Health Professions], 1988; Folder 1:10
  - newsclippings, 1985-1988; Folder 1:11
  - photographs, 1985; Folder 1:12
  - publications, 1985-1990; Folder 1:13
  - publications, 1992-1999; Folder 1:14
  - publications, 2000-2015; Folder 1:15
  - rosters, 1985-1986; Folder 1:16
  - slides [graduation], 1987; Folder 1:17
  - student records, 1985; Folder 1:18